Jagirinawa.
That's definitely the Jagirinawa, Araragi-kun.
Snake Cutter, Snake Rope, or Snake Cutter Rope
It's occasionally called the Serpent, also.
Serpent? So it's a snake?
Oshino, what kind of aberration is the Jagirinawa?
It's an aberration that moves according to one's ill will.
Well, not just ill will alone,
but when someone calls the Jagirinawa, I can't really think of it as anything but ill will.
Ah. I heard about that from Sengoku, too.
The one who put the curse on her was her classmate's friend.
I guess it's a pretty well-known curse among middle schoolers.
Hmm... The Jagirinawa isn't really something that can be controlled by amateurs...
But anyway, why did her classmate's friend want to curse the little lady in the first place?
I heard it was about romance.
The boy the girl liked confessed to Sengoku,
but Sengoku rejected him, unaware of the situation,
and became resented.
Or something like that.
After Sengoku found out that she was cursed
she started reading books about snake curses,
looking into the way to lift the curse, and performed the ceremony.
Killing a snake to release a snake curse seems pretty sketchy to me, though.
What's more, her situation's gotten worse since she started killing snakes.
No. Araragi-kun,
chopping up snakes to counter the Jagirinawa isn't wrong.
In fact, it's exactly right.
Then why?!
She messed up the procedure.
Lifting a curse is harder than casting one.
With an amateur level of knowledge, the situation is bound to get worse.
Plus, she was really unlucky.
I'm back.
Welcome back, Koyomi-oniichan.
How'd it go, Araragi-senpai?
Good. We can release Sengoku from her curse with this.
Really?
Yeah, and we can erase the scale marks, too.
But if we want to remove the curse, we have to do it at that shrine.
Just to be safe, we should do it tonight.
Sengoku, is it okay if you go home late tonight?
Yeah, it's fine. I'll tell my mom that I'm staying at a friend's house tonight.
We'll need several other things for the ceremony.
I'll go get them. In the meantime, you go call your house.
Okay.
Oh, there might be a lot of stuff,
so could you come with me, Kanbaru?
All right.
Sengoku is in danger.
If we don't act tonight, it'll threaten her life.
What?
The Jagirinawa has taken the form of an invisible snake, and it's constantly constricting her body.
The scale marks are the proof.
According to Oshino, if the scales reach her face, she can't be saved anymore.
If it's constricting her, then shouldn't Sengoku-chan be in pain?
Oshino said it should hurt.
She's probably just holding it in.
That classmate didn't have to go so far just because
Sengoku-chan rejected the boy she liked...
No. The curse itself isn't anything special.
Actually, the curse shouldn't even have activated, since it was cast by an amateur.
Then... why?
It seems she made a mistake while trying to break the curse.
She was also pretty unlucky, apparently.
The shrine where the little lady slaughtered the snakes used to be an insignificant place.
That was before Shinobu-chan came...
along with the noble blood of the legendary vampire.
The king of aberrations: the vampire.
Thanks to that, all sorts of bad things started gathering at that shrine.
That's also why you weren't feeling well.
Then...
Yeah, the Jagirinawa activated because she slaughtered the snakes in that shrine.
If she hadn't done it there, everything would've been fine.
That's really like Sengoku-chan hurt herself with her own hands.
Then Araragi-senpai,
wouldn't it be dangerous to do the ceremony in that shrine again?
No. If we follow the procedure correctly, it'll bring out the Jagirinawa.
So it'll actually benefit us.
Hey, Sengoku...
What is it, Koyomi-oniichan?
Those scale marks... They actually hurt, don't they?
Are you okay?
A-About that... Please don't get mad, Koyomi-oniichan.
No. I'm not mad or anything.
I was just wondering if you're okay...
It does feel like I'm being squeezed, but it's not unbearable.
Thinking that you have to hold it in is weird in the first place.
If it hurts, it's okay to say so.
He's right, you know.
Just getting tied up is no big deal, but staying tied up for a while is surprisingly hard on your body.
I have absolutely no clue why you'd say being tied up isn't a big deal,
or why you completely ignored her mental pain, Kanbaru.
Okay, let's go.
Come to think of it, Sengoku...
What is it?
You said there was a boy who confessed to you... Why did you turn him down?
Because...
there's already someone else I like.
Koyomi-oniichan, how much do you remember from back then?
To be honest... not very much.
My memory's not all too great.
Oh, I see...
On the other hand, you really remembered me well.
That's because I didn't really get along with others very much...
Back then, the only one I could play with after school was Rara-chan.
Rara-chan? You mean Tsukihi-chan?
Rara-chan and I ended up going to different middle schools later,
but those times of playing with you and Rara-chan are my most precious memories.
I see.
Plus, I'm an only child.
I was really jealous that she had an older brother.
Kanbaru, are you feeling okay?
Yeah. I'm prepared this time, so it's not as bad as I thought it'd be.
Okay, let's get ready.
Kanbaru, I did tell you to bring clothes that would make it easy to see if
the scale marks were gone or not, but...
Why the hell would you be carrying around a school swimsuit?!
I was just trying to match it up with your preferences...
To hell with your matching!
I notice you don't deny this is your preference.
Sit in the middle, on the sheet.
Hold the charm tightly,
close your eyes, breathe steadily, and then you can start praying.
Praying? To what?
To whatever. Maybe, in this situation...
Okay, I'll do my best.
Go for it.
Koyomi-oniichan, make sure you watch, okay?
Leave it to me.
Please watch over me carefully, okay?
Yeah. Just leave it to me.
Please watch me, Koyomi-oniichan!
No, that's...
That's not true.
You're in sixth grade, but you're not scary at all.
You don't pick on me...
Moreover...
you're really nice.
You even fixed my bike for me.
It is...
not...
Rara-chan's so lucky, having such a nice brother...
Um...
Is it okay if I call you... Koyomi-oniichan?
What's that?
It looks like it's finally breaking.
Yeah, but Araragi-senpai,
now you're in debt to Oshino-san again.
With something this strong, it's going to be a pretty high price, isn't it?
Nah. This time, there's no debt.
Kanbaru, remember when I told you that this was turning into a place where evil things gather?
Yeah.
Such places are dangerous, because they could turn into a spiritual world war at the drop of a hat.
By putting that charm on the shrine, we nipped that in the bud.
It was that dangerous?
Yeah. He said that charm was pocket change in comparison.
This removal ceremony sure takes a while...
I agree, but all we can do is wait.
You know, Araragi-senpai, Sengoku-chan is already really worn out.
Can't we just pull the Jagirinawa off in one go?
Oshino said that I should be able to touch it and even pull it off.
You really shouldn't do that.
If you do, the Jagirinawa will undoubtedly attack you instead.
Plus...
Even if I'm able to get away from it,
it'll just go back to the classmate who placed the curse.
So basically, "What goes around comes around."
Yeah.
"What goes around comes around."
Araragi-kun, I'm repeating myself, but remember that saying and really think about what it means.
Huh?
I don't really know what you're thinking about,
but someday, I'm going to leave town.
When that happens, I won't be able to give you advice anymore.
Aberrations aren't the type to get involved with humans on purpose.
But you're the type of person that jumps in, even when you should leave something alone.
But if it comes to my attention... I just can't help it.
I can't just act like I didn't see anything.
Would it have been better if you just forgot everything like your class rep?
Forgetting everything is...
I guess that was a bit mean.
Well, don't worry about it.
We're pretty good friends now, so I'm not just going to disappear without saying goodbye.
I am an adult, you know. I know the right thing to do, at least.
But since you're already thinking about your future, I think it'd be good to think about that, too.
Basically, what you're saying is that my desire to help people is immature, right?
But Oshino, I can't be like you.
I'm one-tenth vampire -- an aberration.
I can't become someone who exterminates them.
Araragi-kun, if you abandon Shinobu-chan,
you can turn back to a normal human being again whenever you want.
I don't want you to forget that.
Araragi-senpai!
What happened?
I-I don't know. Suddenly...
Did we mess up?
We messed up, didn't we, Araragi-senpai?
No, that can't...
I got it.
Kanbaru, I misunderstood.
What?
If we were just able to see the Jagirinawa, it would've been completely obvious.
What are you talking about?
There wasn't just one Jagirinawa.
There were two!
Damn it!
Stay back, Kanbaru.
It wasn't just the girl who used to be her friend that held a grudge against her.
Sengoku.
The boy she rejected held a grudge, too.
Even if I can't see it...
I should be able to touch it!
This might just work.
Even if you can't see the Jagirinawa, they still leave traces when they move.
All I have to do is listen for moving dirt and watch for parting grass.
I can estimate its location.
Huh?
Araragi-senpai, forgive me!
Kanbaru...
Calm down! Don't get excited!
If you get excited, the poison will spread, Araragi-senpai!
Snakes are fierce animals, but they're cowards!
If you leave it alone, it'll just go away.
But Kanbaru, if I do that,
that snake will just go back to that boy Sengoku turned down!
Araragi-senpai, I'm begging you!
Please don't forget who you're trying to save...
I can't make it anymore.
Even if I want to follow it, chasing invisible snakes is...
impossible for me.
Araragi-senpai.
Sorry... for putting you in such a tough situation...
Sorry.
Please don't apologize. It was necessary.
I'm sorry...
I'm sorry, Kanbaru...
I really am.
The snakes are gone.
They've gone back to those who called them.
Along with the curses they carried.
Koyomi-oniichan.
Kanbaru made the right decision.
For a half-assed aberration like me, standing up to a real aberration is impossible.
I just couldn't give up.
Koyomi-oniichan, thanks for saving me.
Please don't say that, Sengoku. Please.
Please don't thank me.
I don't deserve your gratitude.
I did something unthinkable, and tried to save even the guy who cursed you.
I'm Karen!
I'm Tsukihi!
Its about time to expose just who we are and introduce ourselves properly!
It's too late! It's past too late! It's been far too late!
I wonder how many of them are wondering just who is who!
Probably everyone.
I am Araragi Karen! Araragi Koyomi's little sister!
I am Araragi Tsukihi! Araragi Koyomi's little sister!
A third year student in middle school!
A second year student in middle school!
Together we're the Fire sisters!
Just kidding! I was Tsukihi!
Just kidding! I was Karen!
We switched just in case!
I wonder if you fell for it!
You fell for it didn't you!
Next time! Tsubasa Cat Part 1!
Now, which one am I?
Preview Quiz!